# 今天咱们教点省事儿又好吃的
Today we will teach you something both easy and delicious
# 加点盐 为什么加点盐啊
Add some salt.   What for?
# 网友朋友们好多
Many of our audience
# 都喜欢这个菜  干锅花菜
Are fond of this dish, this dry pot cauliflower
# 酒店基本不能焯水
It can't be blanched in a restaurant in most cases
# 对 一焯水水煮了 成水煮菜了
Yes, once it is blanched, it turns into a stew
# 如果说我在家里边做
It wastes too much oil
# 你要这么多油太浪费了
if you cook like this at home
# 就不用这么着
You needn't do it that way
# 煸点肉片直接把这下去就行
Fry some sliced meat and then pour them into the wok
# 干煸了 在家就可以干煸
That's dry-fry. We can do this at home
# 这个菜花都洗干净弄完了 就怕水
The cauliflower is cleaned, it's afraid of water now
# 这个菜很简单
This dish is easy to cook
# 这蒜一拍 你看齐活
Crush the garlic, well done
# 注意拍蒜 蒜可以大一点 拍蒜才有味
Pay attention to the garlic, the bigger the tastier
# 稍微来点葱 五花肉
A bit of green onion, and then the pork belly
# 来点小米辣 借点辣味
Some "Xiaomila" chili pepper to get spicier
# 别太碎了 太碎了它就不匹配了
Don't dice it too small, or it won't match the size
# 再来点绿的
Some more green onion
# 这小米辣很辣的 不要太多了
The "Xiaomila" chili pepper is so spicy that we just need a little
# 在家里边根据自己的喜好
Add it according to your preferences at home
# 接受辣的程度
According to your acceptance of pepper
# 这点咱们就够了
Such is enough for us
# 来点青蒜 提个味儿 够了
Add some green onion to improve the taste, ok it's enough
# 突然发现师父现在会过了
I suddenly found master thriftier
# 以前您不是教我们要 料要下的足
You taught us to add plenty ingredients before, didn't you?
# 你看这个刚才讲了
I've said just now
# 在家里边直接煸就行了
At home, frying it directly is ok
# 千万别煸烂了
But never fry it too soft
# 如果说你吃着有面感 这菜就失败了
Once you feel it mashy, it's considered a failed dish
# 必须得脆的
It must be crunchy
# 这个菜你说为什么加点盐
Maybe now you know why we add some salt into the cauliflower before cooking
# 你看这个又不一样了
You see, there's a distinction between whether we add some salt first or not
# 你看加点盐 一个是入了味了
That brings two benefits
# 再一个什么 更容易脆了 更脆了
Tastier and crunchier
# 网友朋友们记住了
Remember, my friends
# 师父就教我们小窍门
That's the tip master wannna teach us
# 而且你看下去盐之后
Once you add the salt
# 它（过油的时候）还不容易崩
Oil doesn't spatter when the cauliflower is poured into the wok
# 后边儿的锅烧着呢
The wok is getting hotter now
# 咱们提前把工作预做一下
Let's do some preparation first
# 兑点汁 根据菜花多少可以了
Adding some sauce according to the amount of cauliflower
# 蒸鱼豉油 这是一比一
Seasoned soy sauce for seafood, 1:1 to the sauce
# 这到时候还用放盐什么的么
Shall we add some salt or something else then?
# 不用放 什么都不用放
No, not any more
# 本身这里边就已经有盐味了
It's already salty itself
# 就这点东西就足够了
That's enough
# 酱油 蒸鱼豉油
Soy sauce and seasoned soy sauce for seafood
# 今天咱们教点省事儿的又好吃的
Today we will teach you something both easy and delicious
# 这个油温还是不够
The oil temperature isn't high enough yet
# 油温高一点 得六成热
It should be higher, about 180℃ (60% heat)
# 下去的时候一炸就得了
Just pour it into the wok and fry
# 我们把油都得控好了 你看这一下就得
We gotta drain the oil completely. See, it's done
# 咱们来点底油  把这肉片下去 五花肉
Let's add some base oil and then pour the pork belly into the wok
# 火热咱就撤 这叫控制火候
Controlling the cooking heat by taking away the wok as soon as it's hot enough
# 依次下入蒜煸炒一会
Add the garlic and stir-fry for a while
# 这蒜还可以多点 多点儿它香 金黄色
A little more garlic please, it gives the dish better taste and color
# 再就小米辣 葱 这两个下去了
Then we add the "Xiaomila" chili pepper and green onion
# 这青蒜是不是最后再搁
Do we add the garlic sprout in the end?
# 香气辣气都出来了
It smells good and spicy
# 别死乞白赖的煸这就行了
Don't stir-fry too much, that's enough
# 你看搁里边儿 汁儿
Then we add the sauce
# 咱们顺着这锅边烹汁
Pour it at the edge of the wok
# 你看这香气 锅气
Feel the aroma and "wok hei"
# 然后青蒜倒里边
Then pour the garlic sprout into the wok
# 行了 好嘞
Ok
# 直接倒锅里了 滋啦滋啦的
Pour it into the wok directly, sizzling
# 看看干锅
Look at this dish
# 这菜花多透亮是吧
So bright, isn't it?
# 您瞧这菜花 特别脆 刚刚好
You see this cauliflower, it tastes very crunchy, just right
# 让你说的我这个不吃菜花的
I can't help trying this cauliflower even if I'm not a fan of it
# 我都得尝尝菜花 特别脆
So crunchy
# 而且鲜味香味锅气全出来了 真棒
The savory taste and aroma are circulated. Excellent.
# 刚才你知道为什么要抖点儿盐吧
Now you know why I added some salt just now
# 不抖盐它就很难入味 特别入味
It's hard to be tasty if you don't do that. Now it's particularly tasty.
# 网友朋友们一定要记住 非常清爽
Remember that my friends, and it can be very refreshing
# 不要加那么多酱油 黑乎乎油乎乎
Don't add too much soy sauce, or the dish will be dark and greasy
# 很清爽但是很入味
Now it's refreshing and tasty
# 你看在传承当中
You see, one tip is enough
# 有一个点的技巧就够了
in the process of inheritance
# 你看你搁了盐之后 一个是入味了吧
Once you add the salt first, it enhances the taste
# 再一个你往里下油的时候
Meanwhile, oil doesn't spatter when the cauliflower is poured into the wok
# 那么多水它不崩
Even if the cauliflower is covered with water
# 这窍门在这儿呢
That is the tip